Zachary Shaffer | Resume

1219 Kirkpatrick Avenue, N. Braddock PA, 15104 | (412) 652-6342 | shafferz@allegheny.edu

Objective

My goal, ultimately, is to work as a Software Engineer. I have a passion for the entire process of software development, from planning and outlining the system to testing and releasing the software. I also enjoy working as a front-end Web Developer, as it gives me an opportunity to apply my creative talents to computer science.

Skills & Abilities

Through my time studying computer science at Allegheny College, I have developed a proficiency in the Java programming language. I also have honed my skills in other programming languages, including Python, HTML/CSS, C++, C#, and Ruby. I am proficient when operating on a UNIX based system, such as Linux, and am familiar with Git repositories on both GitHub and BitBucket. Finally, I have extensive experience with many popular software packages, such as the Adobe Creative Suite, Microsoft Office, and the Unity Engine.

Experience

Teaching Assistant — Allegheny College

Jan. 2016 - Present

Working with my colleagues in the introductory Computer Science courses at Allegheny, I ensure that students understand the material and assist them with the lab writing/debugging process. I also hold weekly office hours, and distribute and oversee examinations.

Residence Assistant — Allegheny College

Jan. 2017 - Present

Working to help build a safe and friendly community environment in the dormitories of my campus, I guide my colleagues to the resources they need, help plan and execute building events, and work with the campus staff to keep the residents safe and healthy.

Education

Allegheny College — B.S., Computer Science (In progress)

Aug. 2015 - Present

To date: 68 credits completed towards a Bachelors of Science in Computer Science.

Central Catholic High School — Pittsburgh, PA

Aug. 2011 - May 2015

Leadership

At Allegheny College, I have held the position of Public Relations Officer for two student organizations, where I acted as a liaison to the college community for the clubs. I also have displayed leadership skills in my interactions with my colleagues as both a Teaching Assistant and Residence Assistant at Allegheny College.